Alfonso Gonzalez

💌 alfonso.j.gonzalez@icloud.com 👂 Seattle Wa 🔭 Website 🛮 in LinkedIn 🔘 GitHub

SUMMARY

After 13 years in restaurants, I transitioned to software engineering. A proactive problem solver with a talent for quick learning, Honest, open communication is key to resolving workplace issues. I am fluent in English and Spanish, thriving in fast-paced environments. I seek a team valuing collaboration, and inclusivity, where I can contribute and learn. Also open to self-directed learning and mentorship to expand my skills confidently.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

• Languages and Frameworks:

JavaScript, Ruby, Node.js, HTML/CSS, SQL, Sinatra, MiniTest, Jekyll, Flutter, Dart, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, Mongoose

• Technologies:

GitHub, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Sublime, VSCode, MongoDB Compass

PROJECTS

• Todo List, code on GitHub

A tested Heroku application that allows users to create to-do lists. Created using Ruby, Sinatra, and PostgreSQL.

• Tic-Tac-Toe Web Browser App, link to game 🖸

Browser based app created with JavaScript, HTML and CSS. Published through GitHub pages.

• Rock, Paper, Scissors, Lizard, Spock web app, link to game [2]

Web app game developed with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Spanish Interpreter, Language Line Solutions

May 2023 - present

- · Accurate interpretation services, helping both parties understand and convey their
- Remote, United States
- Serve as a conduit, bridging any language barriers and enabling seamless conversations.
- Contribute to enhancing customer satisfaction and facilitating smooth interactions between clients and their customers.

Mobile Developer, *Activo.today* □

Feb 2023 - present Remote, Puerto Rico

- Collaborating with the app developer to enhance the app's functionality and user experience.
- Contributing to the ideation of new features to improve the app's value proposition and attract new users.
- · Leading the implementation of key features to personalize the user experience, and keep users engaged.

Owner/Operator, La Isla Cuisine Restaurants

Jan 2005 - Nov 2018

Seattle, Wa

- · Hired, trained, and managed multiple teams of employees while building the business from the ground up.
- Created an environment that focused on teamwork, leading by example, and mentorship while encouraging a sense of ownership for my employees.
- Learned to be proactive in solving day-to-day problems that arise in a dynamic environment.

EDUCATION

Ironhack 🛮

Sep 2023 - Oct 2023

· Full stack MERN apps

Remote

Launch School 🛚 2020 - 2023 Remote

• OOP, programming, networking, and database foundations

Bachelors degree in Science, University of Massachusetts 🖸 1998 Amherst